Mss.B.B445
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Weaver, Warren, 1936 September (Box 22, Folder 16)
    Letters making arrangements for Dorothy Wrinch to visit Max Bergmann.
  - Webb, John L, 1937 August - September (Box 22, Folder 17)
    Webb, John L
  - Weed, Lyle A., 1943 December - 1944 January (Box 22, Folder 18)
    Weed, Lyle A.
    Letters requesting samples of papain from Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Weiss, Charles, 1939 June - 1943 May (Box 22, Folder 19)
    Weiss, Charles
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Charles Weiss. Requests for chemical samples. Weiss asks Bergmann to recommend a chemist for the Mount Zion Hospital. Arrangements for a meeting.
  - Weissberger, Arnold, No. 1, 1936 December - 1937 September (Box 22, Folder 20)
    Weissberger, Arnold, No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Arnold Weissberger of the Eastman Kodak Company. Letters concerning chemicals and experiments.
  - Weissberger, Arnold, No. 2, 1937 April - 1944 October (Box 22, Folder 21)
    Weissberger, Arnold, No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Arnold Weissberger of the Eastman Kodak Company. Letters discuss different preparations of chemicals for experimental purposes. An invitation for Max Bergmann to speak at the Rochester Division of the American Chemical Society in 1941.
  - Weiz, Ernestine, 1939 May - 1940 October (Box 22, Folder 22)
    Weiz, Ernestine
    Letters concerning employment oppurtunities for Weiz. Curriculum vitae and letters of recommendation included.
  - Wells, H. E., 1938 February - 1939 January (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Wells, H. E.
    Requests for Max Bergmann to give a series of lectures. Invitation declined.
  - West, Randolph, 1935 September - 1936 April (Box 23, Folder 2)
    West, Randolph
    Correspondence concerning the Harvey Lecture given by Max Bergmann in October, 1935.
  - Weston Electrical Instrument Corporation, 1939 December - 1940 January (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Weston Electrical Instrument Corporation
    Bills for service.
  - Whistler, Roy L., 1938 February - March (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Whistler, Roy L.
    Correspondence concerning a position in Max Bergmann's lab.
  - White, Abraham, No. 1 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    White, Abraham, No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Abraham White. Exchange of reprints. Discussion of experiments. Letters of introduction. Several letters discussing employment in the United States for refugee scientists.
  - White, Abraham, No. 2, 1938 September - 1944 November (Box 23, Folder 6)
    White, Abraham, No. 2
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Abraham White. Letters discussing Bergman's illness.
  - White, Abraham, No. 3, 1935 November - 1942 November (Box 23, Folder 7)
    White, Abraham, No. 3
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Abraham White. Requests and exchange of reprints. Letters discussing experiments.
  - White, Julius, 1934 August - 1939 November (Box 23, Folder 8)
    White, Julius
    Requests for reprints. An application to work in Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Whitmore, F. C., 1942 July - 1943 September (Box 23, Folder 9)
    Whitmore, F. C.
    Correspondence concerning a position at Max Bergmann's lab. Exchange of chemical samples.
  - Who's Who, 1941 October - 1942 October (Box 23, Folder 10)
    Who's Who
    Notice of Max Bergmann's inclusion in the second edition of the "The Chemical Who's Who."
  - Who's Who in the East, 1940 May - 1942 December (Box 23, Folder 11)
    Who's Who in the East
    Notice of Max Bergmann's inclusion in the publication "Who's Who in the East." Includes biographical questionnaires.
  - Wilhelm, R. H., 1941 January - February (Box 23, Folder 12)
    Wilhelm, R. H.
    Invitation to Max Bergmann to give a lecture at a symposium on proteins at Princeton in March 1941.
  - Williams, Dean, No. 1, 1934 May - 1937 August (Box 23, Folder 13)
    Williams, Dean, No. 1
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Dean Williams of the "Journal of the American Leather Chemists Association." Letters concern articles and papers reviewed by Bergmann.
  - Williams, Dean, No. 2, 1941 April - 1944 October (Box 23, Folder 14)
    Williams, Dean, No. 2
  - Williams, Jonathan W., 1938 February - March (Box 23, Folder 15)
    Williams, Jonathan W.
    Williams invites Max Bergmann to speak at an American Chemical Society meeting in Milwaukee, September 1939.
  - Williams, Roger J., 1937 April - 1944 May (Box 23, Folder 16)
    Williams, Roger J.
    Requests for reprints and chemical samples.
  - Williams and Wilkins Company, 1941 November - 1945 March (Box 23, Folder 17)
    Williams and Wilkins Company
    Letters concerning Max Bergmann's subscription to the Journal of Organic Chemistry.
  - Winnick, Theodore, 1939 December - 1944 September (Box 23, Folder 18)
    Winnick, Theodore
  - Winternitz, Milton C., 1941 December - 1942 January (Box 23, Folder 19)
    Winternitz, Milton C.
    Correspondence concerning Winternitz' work on proteins at the Yale University Medical School.
  - Wizinger, R., 1939 December - 1940 January (Box 23, Folder 20)
    Wizinger, R.
    Correspondence concerning the situation of a Dr. Breyer who is stuck in Zurich and wishes to go to the United States. Curricculum vitae included.
  - Wolfrom, M. L., 1941 September - 1942 October (Box 23, Folder 21)
    Wolfrom, M. L.
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and M. L. Wolfrom. Wolfrom writes to Bergmann looking for a refugee scientist to fill a position at Ohio State University.
  - Woolley, D. W., 1942 December - 1944 October (Box 23, Folder 22)
    Woolley, D. W.
    Exchange of reprints. Max Bergmann nominates Woolley to the American Society of Biological Chemists.
  - Wormall, A., 1939 June - 1941 March (Box 23, Folder 23)
    Wormall, A.
  - Wreschner, Marie, 1939 January - February (Box 23, Folder 24)
    Wreschner, Marie
    Correspondence concerning Wreschner's immigration from Germany to the United States. Curriculum vitae included.
  - Wrinch, Dorothy M., 1935 February - 1937 December (Box 23, Folder 25)
    Wrinch, Dorothy M.
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Dorothy Wrinch. Request for reprints. A letter from Bergmann addressing his concern that Wrinch had failed to cite his work in several of her papers.
  - Wu, Hsien, 1938 November - 1940 September (Box 23, Folder 26)
    Wu, Hsien
    Correspondence concerning the arrangements for Chi-yuan Chou's visit to the United States.
  - Wuertz, A. J., 1935 May (Box 23, Folder 27)
    Wuertz, A. J.
    An order for chemical samples.
  - Wuest, H. M., 1941 March - 1944 May (Box 23, Folder 28)
    Wuest, H. M.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and H. M. Wuest. Letters of recommendation. Invitations. Requests for chemical samples.
  - Wycoff, Ralph W. G., 1937 January - 1938 February (Box 23, Folder 29)
    Wycoff, Ralph W. G.
  - Y - Misc., 1939 April (Box 23, Folder 30)
    Y - Misc.
    Requests for reprints. Cross references to other files.
  - Z - Misc., 1936 August - 1943 January (Box 23, Folder 31)
    Z - Misc.
    Requests for reprints. Invitation to an exhibit on "The Contax in Science and Industry."
  - Zamecnik, Paul C., No. 1, 1940 September - 1945 March (Box 23, Folder 32)
    Zamecnik, Paul C., No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Paul Zamecnik. Letters discussing the work of both men. Zamecnik writes expressing his interest in a posittion at Bergmann's lab. Bergmann writes Zamecnik a letter of recommendation. Exchange of chemical samples and reprints. Personal letters.
  - Zamecnik, Paul C., No. 2, 1938 December - 1940 June (Box 23, Folder 33)
    Zamecnik, Paul C., No. 2
  - Zechmeister, L., 1935 December - 1944 May (Box 23, Folder 34)
    Zechmeister, L.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and L. Zechmeister. Zechmeister writes to Bergmann informing him of his appointment at the California Institute of Technology. Letters discussing Bergmann's illness.
  - Zellenka, Gertrude, 1939 May - June (Box 23, Folder 35)
    Zellenka, Gertrude
    Correspondence concerning employment for Zellenka in the United States.
  - Zerner, E., 1940 November - December (Box 23, Folder 36)
    Zerner, E.
    Correspondence concerning employment for Zerner in the United States.
  - Zervas, Leonidas, 1934 May (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Zimmerli, W. F., 1934 November - 1937 February (Box 23, Folder 38)
    Zimmerli, W. F.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and W. F. Zimmerli.
  - Zittle, C. A., 1934 June - 1938 February (Box 23, Folder 39)
    Zittle, C. A.
    Correspondence concerning employment in Max Bergmann's lab.